[dramatic music plays]
[narrator] A long time ago…
Wait a minute.
That's not right. Hang on.
[adventurous music plays]
Perhaps in the distant future?
TSUKUYOMI
Wrong again.
It's neither a long time ago
nor in the distant future.
[grunts]
It's just a teensy bit in the future,
in a world not so different
from the present.
- [gamer 1] A little help here!
- [gamer 2] On it.
[gamer 1]
Your aiming skills are cracked, Iroha!
SAME AS 4 SERVINGS PASTA
DON'T WASTE THEM!!
[gamer 3] Totally.
So when are you gonna go pro?
[Iroha] GGs.
[narrator] This is Iroha,
a perfectly normal high school girl
who also happens to be a gamer.
Due to her not-so-great relationship
with her mother,
she decided to move to Tokyo
and live on her own.
In order to cover those pesky
living expenses and tuition fees,
she somehow managed to make ends meet
- by diligently working part-time jobs.
- No, thank you! Excuse me.
At school, she had all the attributes
to excel in both academics and sports.
She was a model student
admired by her peers.
- [teacher] Miss Sakayori?
- Yes!
"It has been a long time"
sentence structure.
The past participle of the verb "to be",
combined with the auxiliary verb "has"
creates the present perfect tense.
- [students gasp, cheer]
- That is correct.
Nice job.
[chuckles, sighs]
Yikes, that was too close!
I passed out with my eyes still open.
Good thing nobody noticed.
I really lucked out there!
[narrator] As for her other activities…
she prepped for class,
fangirled over her idols,
cried herself to sleep,
played video games…
YACHIYO RUNAMI VR CONCERT
…and fangirled some more
in the VR world with her friends.
IROHA SAKAYORI
Gather around,
for this is the tale of Iroha Sakayori.
- But you can just call her Iroha.
- [sighs]
[narrator, on laptop] I feel very lucky,
- and I'm grateful…
- [yawns]
- …but sometimes I feel so trapped.
- Oh, crap!
Empathizing with other people's pain
is appreciated,
but you have to take care of yourself
- as well.
- [grunting]
- When you're feeling down, it's okay to…
- [sighs]
[narrator] It's just another ordinary day
for this busy bee
and her jam-packed schedule.
[sighs]
Uh, huh?
[narrator] Yeah, so…
Look, she's on her way back home.
Um… [chuckles]
OVER 100 MILLION USERS!
WELCOME TO TSUKUYOMI
- Hi everyone!
- The long-awaited three-day weekend…
- See you all soon!
-…has finally arrived.
For the first time in forever,
I can get a whole six hours of sleep.
YACHIYO RUNAMI
[pop music playing]
♪ I'm missing you again ♪
♪ I'm wanting to see your smiling face ♪
♪ I feel it when you're far away ♪
♪ But even when the rain is falling ♪
♪ Eventually, it dries away ♪
♪ And leaves a rainbow in the sky ♪
[crying]
[narrator]
After being pushed to the limit,
Iroha received a well-deserved break.
♪ Give water to the withered plants ♪
- ♪ We can gather, standing tall again ♪
- [gasps]
♪ I promise it will be all right ♪
A shooting star!
I hope Mikado's wish is granted.
That's all that matters.
Should I make a wish?
Okay.
Please send me money. [chuckles]
[grunting]
♪ In our hearts we've all got a song
It's a precious melody ♪
♪ Straight from your soul
Singing so sweet ♪
♪ And it never stops like a heartbeat
It just keeps driving along ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la-la ♪
[narrator] Lo and behold,
Iroha saw something on her way home.
The base of one of the utility poles
was glowing in seven different colors,
kind of like a gaming rig.
Curious yet weary, she took a closer look.
[sighs]
Just the light messing with my eyes.
- [yelps]
- [narrator] A brilliant light shone
from inside the pole.
[mysterious music plays]
[music stops]
- [music plays]
- [gasps]
[music stops]
[Iroha straining]
- [music continues]
- You're not giving up, huh?
[fussing]
[sneezes]
[baby chuckles]
[narrator] Iroha didn't know
what to do, so she said this.
[groans]
- [gasps]
- [fusses]
[chuckles] Sorry, but I'm kinda maxed
out with life stuff at the moment.
[baby whimpers]
[coos]
[groaning]
- Forgive me, I gotta go!
- [pedestrian] Screw this!
I don't care what happens anymore!
[chuckles]
[cawing]
[Iroha whimpers]
Okay,
maybe this place isn't safe for a baby.
Should I take you
to the police or something?
[breathing heavily]
Geez, how am I supposed
to carry something like this?
[gasps] Hey, wait a minute! Hey!
Excuse me! Open up. You forgot
something really important out here!
[whimpers]
Great,
now I look like some kind of criminal,
kidnapping an innocent baby.
- [coos]
- No, no, no, no, no!
- [crying]
- [gasps]
- Okay.
Good baby. Nice baby.
What am I gonna do?
I can't believe this is happening.
[crying continues]
BANG!
Uh-oh, a bang on the wall.
That's never happened before.
- [crying continues]
- Why are you crying?
There's nothing to be scared of.
[babbles]
- [banging on door]
- [gasps]
HOW TO STOP BABY CRYING
Stop babies from crying.
Hey, how about a lullaby.
That usually works on babies, right?
My memory escapes me.
[baby fussing]
[gasps]
♪ In our hearts we've all got a song ♪
♪ It's a precious melody ♪
♪ Straight from your soul ♪
♪ Singing so sweet ♪
Oh, Yachiyo's songs are magic.
Finally! [groans]
But what am I supposed to do now?
Yeah,
I guess you could call it an incident.
You see, this utility pole
was glowing rainbow colors,
and all of a sudden a kid came out of it.
Uh, I mean a baby.
Yeah, I know it doesn't make any sense.
[chuckles]
I honestly can't
make any sense of it either.
[laughs]
You know, on second thought,
everything's fine.
I apologize for bothering you, officer.
Yes! Thank you very much
and have a good night!
[groans]
I'm exhausted.
[sighs]
Was it a dream? No, it's real.
Wait, was it this big?
It peed itself! [groans]
Seriously?
BABY GOODS
NISHITAKEYA
[Iroha sighs] Why is everything
so expensive in this store?
And diapers are the worst!
[baby babbles]
That'll be 13,243 yen, please.
Fuju~pay.
AVAILABLE FUNDS: ¥23,532
- [Iroha groans]
- [machine] Fuju~!
Why am I doing this
for some random baby I found?
Nope, I'm not gonna think about
my poor life choices until next week.
[snoring]
Huh?
[gasps, yelps]
[sighs]
[soundtrack playing]
What the hell do you know about me,
you hypocrite?
I feel like everything is moving
at such a fast pace nowadays.
- I wonder if I'm gonna be able to keep up.
- [gasps]
[chuckling]
I couldn't understand
what he was talking about.
[sighs]
[Iroha grunts] Heavy.
[child grunts]
A JOURNEY TO TSUKUYOMI
[child] Hey, I'm hungry. Get up, get up.
- Hang on. Give me a second.
- I want milk.
[Iroha groans] Please wait a moment
while I put on the kettle.
- [gasps]
Scary.
[Iroha screaming]
[panting]
Kindly take your leave.
This is seriously freaking me out.
How did you get so big so quickly?
Hmm. Well,
everything moves so fast nowadays,
and life passes you by
in the blink of an eye.
Yeah, things that are a freak of nature.
No thanks.
- [straining]
- [screaming]
Come on, stand up and get out of here.
[yelling]
[groans]
Oh, no. Are you okay?
No, I bumped my head
and now it really hurts! [crying]
Look,
I don't have the time nor the patience
to be babysitting children right now.
GRUMBLE
[stomach grumbles]
[grumbles]
Hmm. I'm hungry too.
[Iroha] 594 yen for takeout.
That's five meals' worth.
And it's 2:00 in the morning.
Here.
Huh? Huh.
[grunts]
What is this magic? It's so good!
- Well, uh, it's omurice, I guess.
- Is that what it's called?
- I love omurice!
- Really? That's great.
I'm glad to hear it.
[Yachiyo on tablet]
Do you have any idea where you came from?
[Yachiyo] …and support me
mean the entire universe to me.
I'd never be where I am today
- if it weren't for all of you.
- [grunts]
[Iroha] Wait, the moon?
[child] Maybe.
[scoffs]
So, why did you come here, Ms. Alien,
to invade us?
[sighs] Now that I think about it,
I honestly don't remember.
Where I come from,
every day was super boring.
I wanted to run away
and find someplace fun and exciting
where I could be happy.
You shouldn't have run away.
What? Why not?
[groans, scoffs]
So anyway, changing the subject,
does this look familiar to you at all?
- Nope. What is it?
- The Tale of the Bamboo Cutter.
A princess from the moon
appears out of a bamboo stalk,
and an old man takes her
and then raises her,
then she's pressured
into getting married and stuff.
What? Married? [grunts]
You came out of a glowing utility pole
instead of a bamboo stalk,
but I have reason to believe
that you're the Princess Kaguya.
- [straining]
- Stop it!
- Hey!
I'm so sorry, what was that again?
- Please continue.
- What?
Okay, that means you're
the old man in this picture. Right, Iroha?
Sure, if it were 80 years from now
and I was a man.
You know how insulting that sounds? Focus!
[laughs]
Wait, back up a minute.
How do you know my name?
On second thought, there's no way that
someone like you is the Princess Kaguya.
[scoffs] I don't even know
what I'm saying anymore.
[child] Hey. So what happens at the end
of the story?
[Iroha] Uh, her people
take her back to the moon.
The old men fought to keep her on Earth,
but unfortunately it was all in vain.
The princess is dressed
in a celestial robe,
she goes back to the moon,
and forgets everything about Earth.
Huh.
Uh. Huh?
It won't move. What happens next?
That's all there is. A happy ending.
What? She goes back
to the moon and that's it?
That's, like, the worst ending ever!
- No!
- [laughs]
Princess Kaguya's
definitely not okay with that ending!
And the fact that it's supposed
to be a heartwarming story
makes it so much worse!
[crying]
That's the way the cookie crumbles,
my friend. Get over it.
I don't want a bad ending,
I want a happy ending!
This is so unfair! I hate it!
[Kaguya babbling]
You can throw a fit all you want.
It's still not gonna change anything.
If its true,
then it's already been decided.
You just have to accept your fate
and be prepared.
That's it.
[gargling, spits]
Figures. I've got more canker sores.
Great.
[sighs]
This three-day weekend went by too fast.
I got it! It's been decided!
I'm gonna make my own happy ending!
And you're gonna be my passenger
on this ride to the grand finale.
Come on!
I don't need a happy ending.
A normal ending is perfectly fine with me.
Listen to what you're saying.
You don't really mean that, do you?
What are you doing? Get away from me,
- you creepy alien!
- You're so mean.
Why can't you just let me sleep?
[groans]
[gasps]
Hmm?
Well, I guess she left.
Maybe it was just a dream
caused by my stressful schedule.
Yes!
Good morning. I'm hiding right here.
Yo, Iroha!
Who's this lady on the Internet
that you constantly watch?
- You really like her?
- That's Yachiyo Runami,
an AI live streamer.
I'm a fan.
[Kaguya] Whoa! AI?
You mean, like,
she's a robot or something?
She can clone herself, sing and dance,
and she's 8,000 years old.
That's her backstory.
Wow, no way!
I gotta go to school. See ya.
No, don't go!
Have you grown again?
- Stay with me. Please don't leave.
- Sorry,
but I can't skip school.
Don't go anywhere.
Look, your food's over there.
Pancakes.
IROHA'S FLOUR AND WATER PANCAKES
[groans]
Ugh, super gross.
Please don't go!
Is school really that important?
More important than anything.
Getting involved with you
was my responsibility,
but I'll make sure
everything goes back to normal.
So, hurry up and remember
how to get back to the moon.
[blows raspberry]
[piano music playing]
This is some assassin-level sleepiness.
Not again.
Would anyone like to
give this piece a shot?
[snoring]
[teacher] Hmm.
That was flawlessly accurate.
- Wonderful!
- Hmm.
[Iroha] At least something's going right.
[sighs] I hope that rapidly growing alien
is behaving herself at home.
TARGET SCHOOL LIST
Keep up the pace and it's totally doable.
I'm confident you can pull this off.
Thanks. That's what I'm striving for.
With all this hard work, I'm sure
your parents must be very proud of you.
Yeah. Well, that would be nice.
[sighs]
There's still plenty of time
until the deadline.
Think this through.
[panting]
Yikes. It's so hot!
- [meows]
- [grunts]
Ah! Come here. [chuckles]
I want one of these cuties.
Can I pick your brain about what
you're gonna do after graduation?
Let me guess.
It's something to do with music,
or maybe e-sports, right?
Seriously?
I don't have that kind of talent.
I highly doubt
my parents would approve of that.
It's either Tokyo University
or something equivalent.
[friend 1] That's the bare minimum?
Super harsh.
[friend 2] Compared to you,
I guess my parents just spoil me rotten.
Thankfully the only thing I don't have
to worry about is being unhealthy,
'cause I ended up with good genes.
[grunts] Hell yeah!
What a great time to be alive.
Wouldn't expect any less
from a superhuman who earns
her own tuition and living expenses.
[Iroha chuckles]
Iroha, you're pushing yourself too hard.
You should learn to take it easy
once in a while.
I'm gonna hit you with some logic.
[Iroha] Okay, I'll take it easy.
- [pedestrian 1] Look at that cute girl.
- [pedestrian 2] Is she stalking someone?
[Iroha]
I wonder if she's okay all by herself.
- [friend 1] It's this way, right?
- Yeah. It's up those stairs.
We've got a surprise for you.
Uh, what do you mean?
A new café opened up.
You promised you'd check it out with us.
- Come on.
- But I don't know if I can today.
Let's go.
I really don't have a lot of free time.
Since Iroha's notes saved us from failing,
behold!
Here's a token of our thanks.
[both] We hope you enjoy your present!
Thanks a lot, you two.
- This looks--
- [Kaguya grunts]
[exclaims]
'Sup, Iroha!
She's so cute!
Iroha, is she one of your friends?
I just noticed she's wearing your clothes.
Do you like pancakes?
- Do you wanna try this one too?
- Huh?
These are pancakes? No way!
They're nothing like the ones Iroha makes.
Uh, well, she's not exactly a friend.
She, uh…
I'm from the moon.
Actually she meant
she's feeling over the moon.
She's my cousin.
I feel the same way.
These pancakes are really delicious.
- What's your name?
- [Iroha stammers] Um…
It's…
It's Kaguya.
- [friend 1] Kaguya! Super cute.
- Right?
Kaguya?
Kaguya!
Kaguya. It's so cute! [chuckles]
[Kaguya gobbling]
[Iroha] Sorry, gotta run.
Thanks for the dessert!
I'll make it up to you both later,
I promise!
- [exclaims]
- [yells]
Wow, it was so nice and cool
in that building, wasn't it?
Why can't your place be like that, Iroha?
Have you completely lost your mind?
What if somebody found out
who you really are?
Why the hell did you leave my place?
- I told you to stay put.
- I left because I was bored.
[grunts] Continue to live recklessly
and you'll end up destroying yourself.
You gotta be more patient
and level-headed.
[gasps]
[no audible dialogue]
[Kaguya] Hey,
can you show me how to use these?
[Iroha] Are those my smart contacts?
Did you bring them?
Nah,
I bought my own pair with your laptop.
What? [groans]
WALLET BALANCE: ¥452
CHANGE FROM YESTERDAY: ¥-124400
I worked so hard to save up money.
I worked so hard
to save all of that money!
Hey, I've got an idea!
Why don't we just go on your laptop
and rewrite the bank info?
We can increase
the numbers in your account.
Absolutely not! What's wrong with you?
No! Don't you dare touch those numbers.
[Kaguya] Hope you're hungry!
[chuckles] Ta-da!
For our first course, we have some
corn potage made with the freshest corn.
Next, a crispy salad with burdock root
and asparagus!
And for the main course, a delicious
hamburger steak simmered in tomato sauce.
Last but certainly not least, zucchini.
You used my money for this too,
didn't you?
Well, of course. Impressed?
[screeches] Huh?
[whimpers]
[Kaguya] Eat.
Now I'm poor and destitute
without a yen to my name.
I've been working endlessly
to pay for my tuition.
What the hell? This is delicious.
Who even are you?
I can't remember the last time
I had a meal this good.
All my body wants to do is cry.
Is the last of my money worth it? [groans]
You devil.
What are you talking about?
I'm not a devil.
I'm Kaguya.
[Iroha groans]
[crying] You're so annoying.
- Damn, it's good.
- [chuckles]
Hey, listen.
I cannot possibly keep hiding you here.
I'm already dealing with a lot,
like living on my own
against my parents' wishes.
I just don't want any trouble, okay?
Ah! [humming]
[humming]
It's done!
[gasps] Why are you on my laptop?
You're not doing
anything illegal, are you?
Nah, I bought a mobile gaming kit!
Now InuDOGE can always be with me
wherever I go!
By the way, what kind of grub do you want
to tickle your taste buds tomorrow?
Any requests?
She's planning on living here forever,
isn't she? [groans]
Well, of course I have to live here.
Where else am I gonna go?
What if a scientist finds me and they want
to put me in a lab and dissect me?
Help! [screams]
Uh.
[sighs]
You can stay until someone picks you up.
For real?
Don't stand out.
- Don't go outside without permission.
- [groans]
And don't get in my way.
As long as you follow these three
simple rules, then you can stay here.
What? So you're saying I'm doomed
to live my life in a prison,
confined without any fun
or human interaction!
You said you're gonna make
your own happy ending.
Just don't get me involved.
[blows raspberry]
Let's pretend this conversation
didn't happen.
But I want a happy ending together.
- Please. Pretty please?
- [whistling]
Stop that!
Ignoring me is strictly forbidden!
- [grumbles]
- Seriously?
ALARM
[gasps]
[groans]
- My homework.
- No!
Where are you going?
Please don't leave me behind again.
I'm begging you to spare my life.
I can't spend another minute
in this boring, charmless,
decrepit place all alone! Please.
WELL, SORRY MY APARTMENT'S UGLY…
I'm serious, you can only stay
till someone collects you.
Got it?
Oh, that's right!
You have to pay for your own food!
More rules?
[chuckles]
[gasps]
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Oh.
Huh? Iroha, where'd you run off to?
Wait! It's Yachiyo!
You're Yachiyo, right?
The sun has finally set
and night begins to fall.
[gasps]
[Yachiyo chuckles]
Welcome to the virtual world
of Tsukuyomi, friend.
I'm the caretaker, Yachiyo Runami!
- This fun little fluff's FUSHI!
- [chuckles]
Yachiyo brought Tsukuyomi to life
and created me too!
Now, before you head out there,
that attire is a little unbecoming,
don't you think?
[Kaguya gasps, chuckles]
Okay. Wow,
these clothes look super adorable!
And I love this hairstyle.
[Yachiyo] Perfect, I think you're ready
to join the rest of us.
Come on. Off you go!
[yells]
[chuckles]
[screams, chuckles]
[grunts]
Blonde, huh?
Princess Kaguya's trendy.
Hod up. Are you Iroha?
- Who's that little guy?
- No way! It's InuDOGE.
I didn't know you could come in here.
[barks]
[gasps]
Let's go.
[Kaguya] Let's go.
[adventurous music plays]
This is so cool!
[FUSHI]
Congratulations on your very first login!
In Tsukuyomi, everyone is a creator.
If you can warm the hearts
and impress the other members,
then the admins
will reward you with a Fuju~!
To kick things off,
here's a welcome login bonus!
You can also use your Fuju~
to support your favorite creators,
who work tirelessly
to provide unlimited entertainment.
[gasps]
[Kaguya] Awesome sauce!
I can't believe how much cool stuff
is in this place!
[shrieks, chuckles]
So happy!
[chuckles]
Even a poor person like me can really
enjoy everything Tsukuyomi has to offer.
[sighs, exclaims]
[groans]
I can't taste it.
They haven't been able to create
virtual taste and smell simulators.
Don't they sell the real thing anywhere?
Well, you can order whatever you want
and have it delivered.
But then you have to pay for it
with real money that I don't have.
The best I can do
is make a little money playing games.
I don't have any special skills
to make some serious cash.
It's time. Come on.
[fans chattering]
[fan 1] I can't wait!
Ah.
[chuckles]
By the way, Iroha,
I talked to Yachiyo earlier.
[shushes]
That was just the tutorial program.
You'll see the real thing in a minute.
[fan cheers]
Yo! What's up, everybody?
Let's get this party started
in Tsukuyomi tonight!
We've got a spectacular Yachiyo concert!
And it's being broadcast live
to all of Tsukuyomi.
So, grab your popcorn,
because the show's about to begin!
[all] Ten! Nine!
Eight! Seven!
Six! Five! Four!
Three! Two! One!
[gong sounds]
Hi, everyone.
[chuckles]
Are you ready?
Then let's do this.
Did you all have a wonderful day?
[crowd cheers]
[exclaiming]
[chuckles]
Let's go!
Tonight I'm taking you all
on a spectacular adventure!
It'll be the trip of a lifetime!
♪ I've waited for you ♪
♪ Can't believe we finally met ♪
♪ It must've been a thousand years ♪
♪ And now I never wanna lose you ♪
♪ So just grab my hand ♪
♪ And don't let go ♪
[vocalizes]
♪ Hey now
If you listen close enough ♪
♪ You can hear the sound of stars
Coming down all around us ♪
♪ Hey now, come on closer
Listen up ♪
♪ There's a brand-new world that's waiting
Where anything's possible ♪
♪ Let's hold hands
Let's hold hands and just dance ♪
♪ And when we hear the tune playing loud
We'll know ♪
♪ We can sing, la, la, la ♪
♪ Ringing out, la, la, la ♪
♪ And even if the path to walk
Looks dark ♪
♪ The moonlit sky
Will light the way for us ♪
♪ I wonder if you'll see the sky ♪
♪ If you'll smell the ocean around you ♪
♪ Or have you paid attention all along? ♪
♪ So no matter when ♪
♪ And no matter where you might be ♪
♪ You know that
I'll be watching over you ♪
♪ Go on and count up all the days
When you laughed so hard ♪
♪ And you
Can weave them all together now ♪
♪ And even the thought
Of what our future will bring ♪
♪ Is sure to have my heart singing ♪
♪ Singing ♪
♪ And it'll all come true ♪
♪ I'll write my story
And journey on with you ♪
[music ends]
- Ah.
- [Iroha crying]
[crowd cheering]
Yachiyo…
Hmm?
[fan 2] Yachiyo!
Yay! Sending sprinkles of gratitude
and joy with a cherry on top to you!
[chuckles] I'm so lucky
to have such wonderful friends and fans.
Oh! It's announcement time.
We're hosting an exciting event
called the Yachiyo Cup!
[FUSHI] All you awesome Tsukuyomi
streamers are eligible to participate.
Here's your challenge.
The streamer who gains
the most new followers in one month
will be declared the winner!
The prize for the winner
will be an exclusive opportunity for
a live performance collab with Yachiyo!
Let's work together
to create the most breathtaking
live collab performance in the world!
- [both chuckle]
- A collab?
- Is this event a big deal?
- Of course it is!
I mean, she's done collabs
with other streamers,
but she's never
performed live with anyone before.
- This is insane! Who's it gonna be?
- [gasps]
Come on, Iroha. Let's compete!
There's no way she'd perform
with nobodies like us.
Usually these kinds of things
are prearranged anyway. It's all for show.
- Yachiyo!
- Hmm!
[growls]
[fans scream]
Yo! What up, my little rabid bunnies?
Your Mikado has arrived!
[crowd cheers]
Ha!
[dramatic music playing]
Let's do that too. I wanna try that epic
fighting stuff just like they're doing!
[music continues]
[crowd cheering]
Perfect. Another festival has begun.
An arrow of love to your heart.
[chuckles] Meow.
Just end this charade and say we won, okay?
I'll give you all a performance
that'll feel like a dream!
[crowd cheering]
Wow, look at all the sparkles. [chuckles]
It's been decided.
We're gonna win this competition.
Looking forward to that collab…
[kisses] …Yachiyo.
Wha…
If you win, I'll happily oblige.
But let's see what fate has in store.
I promise it'll be
the most spectacular concert.
So good luck to all the participants.
Let's share the joy,
and seal it with a happily ever after!
Happy ever after…
[groans]
- Hmph.
- [chuckles]
Yachiyo!
- [FUSHI grumbles]
- [chuckles]
I, Kaguya, will win the Yachiyo Cup!
That collab performance is gonna be mine!
[muffled chatter]
[whistles]
What an adorable girl.
Are you crazy? You can't just
say and do whatever you want.
That's a wrap.
I hope you enjoyed today's concert.
I'd love to have a quick chat
with all of you before I leave.
- Have a good night!
- Good night!
This event is gonna be fun.
Later! Stay cute now,
my good little bunnies!
[Iroha] Have you already forgotten
the promise you made?
Iroha, let's do this together!
- No! It's not gonna work.
- No! That's not gonna happen.
Be nice.
[Iroha gasps] Yachiyo?
You forgot something.
I'm afraid the Yachiyo Cup competition
is only open to streamers. Sorry!
Hmm. That's right!
Then I guess
I'll have to become a streamer!
Let's get ready, Iroha.
[gasps] Uh, sorry.
- Uh, I'll be going too.
- Please wait.
You forgot something.
[Iroha stammers]
- Thank you very much!
- [chuckles]
Thank you so much for always coming here.
Iroha.
[keyboard clacking]
How to become a streamer.
Whoa, how are you blonde?
What? You don't like it?
Okay. [grunts]
[Kaguya grunting]
Nah, I like this one the best. [chuckles]
Yep, there's no doubt about it.
She's definitely an alien.
This is just beyond
the bounds of comprehension.
Okay, let's see now.
What should I do as a live streamer?
Hmm.
I guess I could try that fighting stuff
we saw earlier. [chuckles]
Yo, Iroha! Can you teach me that?
- That cool fighting stuff!
- [groans]
[groans]
WORK, STUDY, WORK, FOOD
- Right.
- What?
What is this?
[Iroha] This is my summer break schedule.
[whimpers] You can't be serious.
I don't see anything about playtime.
I can't waste a single day.
So that means don't bother me.
What?
That's so unfair!
Ow! Ouch!
If you wanna live here…
[growls]
What is that crap?
It's for streaming!
Don't worry,
I got it from the dollar store.
Check it out! Look! I started streaming.
What do you think? [chuckles]
HELLO FROM THE MOON!
Yoo-hoo! Hi, everyone.
My name is Kaguya and I'm from the moon!
I can't think of anything to do today,
so that's all for now!
[guitar playing out of tune]
Catch you later!
Uh, how do you turn this off?
[Iroha] No, no, no.
What was that god-awful, unsettling,
cringeworthy dissonance?
That's my jingle.
- [humming]
- [groans]
Stop, please.
Hold on. How did you make that music?
[grunts, gasps]
Did you use my keyboard?
You can't just take things without asking!
Ha-ha!
You can play this, can't you, Iroha?
I couldn't figure it out
for the life of me. [chuckles]
Okay. I'm ready
for my first lesson, teacher.
First of all,
there are these combinations…
…called chords.
[young Iroha laughing]
[parent 1 chuckles]
Iroha, music is something
you should enjoy freely.
[parent 2] If you're going to play, then
you should play with a flawless intent.
[young Iroha]
Then I don't wanna play anymore.
[exclaims]
[grunts]
[playing lively song]
[squeals]
- Wow!
- How does that sound?
[chuckles] That was amazing!
You're a genius!
[chuckles] Not really.
I can do a lot of things
but I'm not perfect.
Oh.
[chuckles] One more time.
I want you to make it endless.
[plays dramatically]
[cheering]
Oh, lightbulb!
If you write me a song and I sing it,
then it'll definitely go viral!
[chuckling]
Write a piece for me, pretty please.
No, a cover song will do just fine.
No!
I want an original piece!
I wrote this a long time ago
at kind of a dark time in my life.
Sorry, but I don't have any time
to write anything new for you.
[cheers]
Wow.
Did you really write all of these songs?
Wowee!
Glad you like them.
You can just sing them however you want.
[humming]
♪ And now nobody can keep me down ♪
♪ And I just can't help myself
But sing ♪
Iroha, produce this.
And with our powers combined
we can win the Yachiyo Cup together!
In this old shabby apartment
begins the tale of our triumph!
What do you mean? It's not shabby.
- I can't.
- What? No!
But it'll be so much fun!
Look, I said you could stay here
as long as you don't get in my way.
[yelling]
Please, Iroha. I beg of you.
Nope. Not falling for that.
[sniffles] But I don't want our story
to end like this.
All I ever wanted was a happy ending,
you know?
[groaning]
You're really making this hard to resist.
THE ROAD TO THE YACHIYO CUP
8910TH PLACE - KAGUYA
[upbeat music playing]
[no audible dialogue]
Nah, I don't care about that.
What's the sense in worrying?
Just move on, right?
[yelling]
That's the worst ending ever.
I can't handle this garbage. Damn it!
3006TH PLACE
40594 FANS
♪ Let's disrupt the rules
For how we live our lives ♪
♪ Think out of the box
Color outside the lines ♪
♪ Let's repaint the world in our design ♪
♪ Being dull's a drag ♪
♪ And I can't really do that ♪
♪ I'm gonna pave my path ♪
♪ So if you're sticking out your tongue
Then bring it on! Let's go! ♪
DON'T YOU DARE UPLOAD THIS!
[Iroha] For an alien,
you fit in a little too well.
Also, I don't think Princess Kaguya
is supposed to be this cheerful.
So, what do you wanna eat today?
[music continues]
[Iroha] Why am I doing this?
It isn't like me.
[Kaguya] ♪ I wanna know more
Get out and explore ♪
♪ Get a taste of the world ♪
♪ And now nobody can keep me down ♪
♪ I just can't help myself
But sing ♪
THIS STREAM HAS ENDED
[chuckles]
This new girl's totally wild.
♪ Instead of giving up ♪
WATASHIHA WATASHINOKOTOGA SUKI
KAGUYA
[music stops]
[Kaguya] Hmm…
Your last singing stream was amazing.
I was on the edge of my seat
the whole time.
Totally.
You're awesome at both video games
and singing.
Aw, thanks. Guess I'm multitalented.
[friend 1]
Your original song was fantastic too.
- [friend 2] Super catchy.
- [humming]
Hear that? I'm so happy for you.
Wait. Did you compose that song, Iroha?
Check out beauty and the brains
over here being all modest.
Oh, no. I wrote that song
a really long time ago.
Kaguya, don't put me in the spotlight.
It's unnecessary.
It's not enough. I need to do more.
What should I do?
I need some help. [groaning]
Uh, well,
you've already tried so many things.
I guess the only option left
is for Iroha to finally drop the facade
and take off her costume.
[yelps]
Hey, I'm kidding. I was just kidding.
[Kaguya] Singing is the way to go!
Besides, all the nerds were happy too.
[Iroha] Don't call them nerds.
So, Iroha, can you make me a new song?
Maybe you could sing with me too.
I told you, I can't cut into my work
and study time any more than this.
But you're at the beach right now!
Hmph. True elites don't neglect their
playtime, they just work around it.
They'll even cut back on sleep
if necessary.
[Kaguya] That's super twisted.
[groans]
This is turning into
one big epic fail. [groans]
Nobody can do this but you.
Please help me.
I want you to create a beautiful song.
[groaning]
Well, I…
All right, If I have time.
- Let's go!
- [groaning]
Tag team streaming sensation,
- Kaguya and Iroha!
- Why can't I ever say no to her?
- It's not fair.
- Iroha's a softy.
- Didn't know she was a pushover.
- [chuckling]
[Iroha gasps] What's with the crabs?
- [shrieking]
- They were chilling on the rocks!
I'm gonna gather a bunch of them
and make an army!
- [laughs]
- [yelling]
Uh.
You know, Iroha seems a lot happier.
Before Kaguya showed up,
it seemed like she would
just fade into the background.
[all chuckle]
[both] What's your secret?
Did you use magic?
- Uh.
- [both] Hmm?
[music resumes]
♪ Instead of giving up
When a what-if comes around ♪
♪ I want a what-if
To be a break you found ♪
♪ Don't you think it's a waste
Never to fly ♪
♪ Keeping your feet on the ground ♪
IROHA'S BUSY!
TEACH ME HOW TO GAME!
[Iroha] Okay! Are your ready for an
awesome video game collab stream?
Roka! Mami!
Teach me how to play this!
[Mami] The hottest game that everyone
is playing right now is called KASSEN.
[grunts, gasps]
[yelps]
[screaming]
- [chuckles]
- Whoa.
[Roka]
This is basically a territory battle.
You gotta invade one of the towers
on the left or right.
If you can defeat the ox demon
and capture his territory,
then you unlock a special weapon.
[Kaguya] Here we go!
[Roka] You gotta blast that into the keep!
Ah!
Wow, Kaguya!
You're a natural at this game.
VICTORY
VIEWS
[Kaguya] Kaguya's pro tip.
If you really want to enhance
the flavor of the clam broth,
you can shuck them raw and wash them…
MARRY ME, KAGUYA!
[Iroha grunting]
- [fan 1] Will you marry me?
- [fan 2] I want to marry you.
- [fan 3] Marry me.
- [fans clamoring]
Here's the thing,
none of you guys have ever met me IRL.
I'm kind of selfish
and get violent easily.
I'm a huge pain in the butt.
You're actually aware of that?
I'm just an adorable little troublemaker.
I'LL SPOIL YOU!
STEP ON ME!
- [fan] Marry me.
- Ah-ha!
If you can beat Iro P,
then I'll marry you!
I'm calling it Battle For Kaguya
KASSEN Tourn…
STREAM COMING SOON
LIKE AND SUBSCRIBE PLS!
[groans] What the hell were you thinking?
Cancel that right now!
Sorry I got carried away.
Please protect me, Iro P.
[sighs]
[bell dings]
[yells]
[groaning]
[grunts]
[samurai 1] Watch me.
You gotta dodge and evade like this.
[groans]
[gamer]
What the hell's with that skin's hitbox?
[gamer 2] Oh, no. This is gonna be bad.
[Kaguya] Flawless victory!
[chuckling]
Just so you know,
this can all disappear overnight.
It's a risky business.
True. But it's all still legal, correct?
[groans]
At least clean up after yourself.
[Kaguya] But cleaning is so boring.
- [barks]
- [Iroha] Hey,
are you really sure
you want me to go with you?
[chuckles]
Yeah. I-ro-ha!
- [Iroha] What is that?
- It's our special handshake!
You know, 'cause we're besties.
[Iroha] Yeah.
Huh? No! [screams]
I died!
- No way! Seriously?
- [groans]
This is insane!
The developers show no mercy!
[groans]
Will you shut the hell up and go to bed?
Huh? What is it?
[stammers]
[groans]
[Kaguya] Lookee here.
What about this place?
[sighs] You'd go crazy
living in a place like that.
It's so big.
Aw!
- [breathes heavily]
- Did you find something on the ground?
Iroha?
I'm okay.
Iroha? [gasps]
You're burning up! What's wrong?
Iroha?
[grunts]
No. My shift!
Iroha! Are you okay?
I'm fine. I gotta get to work.
- [gasps]
- [groans]
I called them and said you couldn't
make it. I told them you were sick.
Iroha, please. You have to rest.
[whimpering]
SORRY YOU'RE SICK!
YOUR SISTER'S REALLY SWEET.
I put a lot of fluffy items around you.
So you get comfy cozy, okay?
Thank you so much, Kaguya.
Oh! Hospital, hmm.
Let's go to the hospital, okay?
I can't. It costs too much.
Don't you worry about that.
I'll take care of it.
But…
I had everything planned out
to the last minute.
If I take a few days off,
I'll never be able to catch up.
And then I'll never be able to
get a scholarship.
Uh.
I get that. But why do you always
have to work so hard all by yourself?
[crying]
[Kaguya crying]
I know I asked too much of you
with the streaming.
Iroha,
- I don't want you to die.
- [chuckles]
So dramatic.
I'm not going to die.
But people die so easily in the movies!
[crying]
Huh?
[Iroha] So, when I agreed to cover both
my tuition and living expenses on my own,
they finally accepted my decision.
You make it sound so easy,
but no one else ever goes to that extreme.
My mom did the same thing
and she got by without any problems.
And there was no way
I was gonna back down.
I still remember the first time
I woke up in this place.
First time living alone.
There was nothing in here.
And I didn't want to rely on anyone.
When I decided I was going to
take care of myself,
it gave me this surge of energy.
Lucky me.
What are you talking about?
That's not lucky at all!
I bet even aliens from other planets
think your mom is totally crazy!
Crazy! Crazy!
- [groans] Crazy!
- Kaguya…
Huh?
[sighs] Sorry.
Why am I talking about this stuff?
- [pot boiling]
- Oh!
Oh, no!
Today's meal is green onion miso
with ginger and egg-rice porridge.
[sped-up]
First mix a ton of bonito flakes and…
[normal] Two eggs for more protein.
Make sure you blow on it before
you eat it, because it's really hot.
[gasps]
It's delicious.
Hmm.
Victory!
[exciting music plays]
What's up, Tsukuyomi fans? Otako here.
Your good, loyal doggy!
OTAKO THE LOYAL DOG
Here to bring you the latest.
Are you ready for an update
on the Yachiyo Cup?
Here are the top ten from this week.
Keep an eye
on the official slate for the top four.
Is your favorite streamer listed?
Now, on to the top three!
LET'S HAVE A WARM, COZY CHAT!
In third place, the idol with
the soothing voice, Nukumi Yukumo!
In second, the high spec elf,
Tereriri Tietate!
TETETE FOR SHORT!
Last but not least, as expected,
far ahead of everyone else…
Who's in first place?
The one and only, Black onyX!
1ST PLACE
BLACK ONYX
No competition.
Is it time to go home yet?
Thank you all so much
for your continued support.
Has it been decided that these
are the final top three?
Not just yet.
There's a brand-new team in town
that's crushing the competition right now.
Do you know who they are?
I'm counting on some wild shake-ups
and shifting scales.
I'm looking forward to the final outcome!
[both] Yay!
Hey, girl. How are you feeling?
I'm fine now.
1ST PLACE
BLACK ONYX
[groans] How am I supposed to
compete with them?
[Roka] Black onyX is tough to beat.
Well, of course. It's because of Mikado.
[groans] Mami, how could you betray me?
I'm rooting for you
as my second place pick.
I'm trying to win.
Therefore, you have to root for me only!
[Mami, in Japanese] ♪ To, to, to the top ♪
Damn it! Mikado and I
should just fight it out. Pow!
A match between Kaguya and Mikado
isn't a bad idea.
It'd be the game of the century.
Hell yeah! [laughs]
Terrible idea.
He's on a completely different level.
He's a pro gamer.
Oh, come on!
[grunts] Let's do it.
I'm putting my foot down. No, no, no!
Iroha, I want you to help.
Wait, no. No, no, no.
I don't want you to collapse or anything.
However… [groans]
Maybe playing a game
would be a nice break?
- [scoffs]
- [stammers]
Would you even care
if someone came and took me away?
Surprisingly,
no one's come to retrieve you yet.
[grumbles] Well, sure.
But you never know, they might show up
one day out of the blue!
[groans] I wish they'd come sooner
rather than later.
Please, take her away!
Hey! Now you're just being mean.
Question. How long have you been here
and you still don't know who you are?
- [Kaguya grunting]
- Huh?
[Kaguya, singsongy] Happy ending!
I need a happy ending!
- I need a happy ending!
- [gasps]
- [Iroha] I can't hear you!
- [Mami grunting]
…gonna be a magical happy ending!
Huh?
TO LADY KAGUYA
[shrieks]
Huh, you're kidding, right?
[groans]
MESSAGE FROM BLACK ONYX
MIKADO AKIRA
I'VE GOT A LITTLE PROPOSAL…
[Mami] Whoa, check this out.
I caught a really big one!
HOW ABOUT A KASSEN SHOWDOWN,
[commentator] Whoo-hoo!
Get ready!
The main event is about to begin!
The reigning champion, Black onyX
has challenged,
and proposed marriage to the rising stars
Kaguya and Iro P,
who have been climbing the ranks
at an unprecedented rate!
[Otako] Mikado's fandom
was briefly troubled by the news,
but brushed it off as just joking around.
[commentator] So, grab some popcorn,
because the biggest
KASSEN battle of the year
to decide their destiny, is happening now!
Hi, there.
I'm your commentator, Koto Okkoteru.
And I'm your good, loyal doggy, Otako!
[Koto] With only one hour left
until the results
of the Yachiyo Cup are announced.
[Otako] Could the results of this match
bring Kaguya and Iro P out on top?
43RD PLACE
KAGUYA/IRO P
The rules are SENGOKU,
a best two out of three,
with three players on each team.
[Koto] Right.
We're just waiting on Black onyX.
[all] Huh?
[fast-paced music plays]
[Koto] Wait a minute.
Where are we, on the island of ogres?
[Koto gasps] Whoa!
They were right here on the stage.
And Black onyX is here!
[crowd cheers]
[Mikado] Why, hello.
- [chuckles]
- I'm glad you're here.
Thank you for accepting this match.
Oh, uh, Mikado,
I'm a really big fan of yours.
MAMIMAMI
Mami, my apologies.
But I won't go easy on you.
[gasps]
He said my name.
[Iroha] Mami?
Mami!
So, there's my beautiful princess, Kaguya.
Shut up, Mikado! Get ready to fight!
[chuckles] I just love
your fighting stance. It's really cute.
Kaguya, if I win,
won't you please marry me?
[Iroha] As if!
That's never gonna happen. [yells]
[grunts] Feisty.
If Iroha says no, the answer's no!
[Iroha stammers] You idiot!
How many times do I have to tell you?
[Kaguya] Uh,
I think we should check on Mami.
[Iroha] No good. She's not waking up.
No! But we need three people!
Ta-da!
You rang?
Really? Yachiyo's gonna join the party?
[chuckles]
How quickly you forget.
I was on your side last time, remember?
[Iroha grunts]
Huh?
Let's win this game! [chuckles]
[Iroha] So, do we have a strategy?
What should we do?
Rush in like hi-yah! And then we run.
Rapid-fire moves. Bam!
- Yeah!
- [groans]
- [horn blows]
- [Koto] All right, here we go!
[adventurous music plays]
[Koto] Huh, whoa!
TriDEnt! It's TriDEnt!
Black onyX is separating
into different lanes!
[Otako] TriDEnt means taking on
multiple enemies all by yourself.
It's not something just anyone
can pull off without serious confidence.
Well, that's an interesting approach.
They're underestimating us.
Huh? [grunts]
We can't fly anymore.
- Let's land.
- Uh-huh.
[Kaguya] Wait for me!
[grunts]
[both straining]
So, Kaguya said your name's Iroha.
[Iroha] Nope.
Sorry, I'm afraid you're mistaken.
[grunts]
Iroha!
What did I say?
[Mikado] Wake up. Hello.
I really appreciate you wearing this skin.
It's way too easy to hit.
You sure you don't regret wearing that?
Come on. Show me what you got.
Uh, what?
Iro P actually took off her costume!
All right. Knew it was you.
I'm glad to see you're doing well.
Yeah. Well, it's all thanks to you!
Why don't you come here
and give your big brother a hug?
Or would you rather
have a nice pat on the head?
What? Big brother?
[fast-paced music plays]
There you go. Got ya!
Your sniping skills are truly terrifying.
Looks like it's impossible
to hit her the usual way.
[Mikado] By the way,
Mom's been worried about you.
You should at least contact her.
[Iroha] Sorry, I've been a little busy
with my own life!
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
You both take things too seriously.
That's why you don't get along.
Mom's just waiting for you to screw up.
Shut up! Stop trying to get in my head!
[Kaguya screams]
You should handle the situation better.
Just like me.
[Koto] Insta-kill!
- [Otako] That was in record time.
- [groans]
[Koto] Into the bottom lane,
Yachiyo has also defeated the archdemon!
[grunts]
[Koto] Noi manages to slow her down.
[Otako] And not a moment too soon.
Ow.
Well played, Noi. The whole time
your goal was to hold me back. [groans]
[Koto] Noi has taken the tower!
[Iroha] They took the tower?
We're in trouble already, aren't we?
- Ow!
- [grunts]
[Mikado] Focus, ladies.
Don't get distracted now.
- Too predictable.
- [Kaguya shouts]
You need some new moves!
That actually hurts, you know?
[strains]
[bell tolls]
[Otako] The end-of-round-one TriDEnt
is still in place,
and they've taken both towers. Incredible!
[Koto] Kaguya and Iro P
are definitely holding their own!
However, Black onyX is just too strong!
[Iroha] There's a huge gap
between our skill differences.
There's no chance.
[Yachiyo] I'm so sorry.
I fought like a sea slug the entire time.
Not at all, Yachiyo!
You're the strongest out of all of us.
Hmm.
Oh, hey, is Mikado a…
[dramatic music playing]
[Otako] Welcome to round two!
Black onyX has once again decided
to continue with the TriDEnt setup!
[Mikado] Kaguya, I know you must be
frustrated after round one,
but continue with this strategy,
it'll be a repeat of last time.
Hmm?
[Iroha grunts]
[grunts]
So where's Kaguya?
She went back to the moon.
[chuckles] Don't joke!
[Mikado] The hammer isn't exactly
a stealthy weapon.
Where is she?
Huh? Up there?
There we go.
[shouts]
[Mikado] Rai,
we need support in the top lane!
Noi's getting taken out.
Don't lose focus now, big brother.
Nice. Well done.
Noi's accuracy is too good.
Someone close in on him or something.
[shouting]
Now it's our turn to take the lead.
Till next time.
[both panting]
Just a little more to go.
We got this in the bag.
[breathes shakily]
I knew this was too much for me.
- [Kaguya shouts]
- [Mikado grunts]
[hums, laughs]
[Koto] Comeback!
Team Kaguya and Iro P has won round two!
[squeals]
Mikado, you really suck.
[Koto]
Kaguya's clever tactic actually worked!
[Otako] She took advantage of the fact
that the 2D map lacks
height and altitude data.
[Koto gasps] I never thought of that!
[laughs] Genius!
[Otako] Round three
will decide the winner!
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
Hats off to you, Kaguya.
I wonder what would've happened if
I changed my strategy in round two though.
Hmm. We both hate to lose,
don't we, Mikado?
If I were me,
why would I ever change my strategy?
I mean, if it isn't broke,
don't fix it, right?
So, have I shattered your image
of the Kaguya you see on my streams?
[laughs]
Well, you've certainly changed
my perspective.
- There's more to you than meets the eye.
- [Noi sighs]
Don't worry. We'll take care of Yachiyo.
[Noi grunts] You sure you can handle
this all by yourself, Mikado?
Yep.
[Noi] All righty, then.
[parent] So, you're the lead in this,
aren't you, Iroha?
That's wonderful. Lots of luck.
Well, I, uh…
Mami said she really wanted the lead,
so I said it was okay.
- [thud]
- [chair scrapes]
[parent] So you'll just give anything
away if someone asks for it,
even if it's important?
Hey, Mom. It's okay.
There are plenty of things
she won't give away.
[brother]
Mom, I'm going to Tokyo next week.
[Mom] Really? That sudden?
[brother] It's what I want.
[Mom] All right.
[young Iroha] Why'd he leave?
Now I'm gonna be all alone.
Why?
[Koto] Here we go!
Each team has taken a tower,
but the battle is getting intense
near team Kaguya's keep.
[groans]
[Mikado] Iroha gets emotional
way too easily,
and Kaguya's too self-centered and brash.
Is this over yet?
So, Iroha, about those weapons?
[Iroha] I'm totally useless.
But I don't want to give up!
Iroha!
Remember, you're never alone.
You can always rely on Kaguya and myself.
So, no worries.
- Mmm. Understood.
- Uh…
I'll leave this to you, Yachiyo.
[Kaguya groans]
Respectfully acknowledged,
and now let the festival begin!
Kaguya and Iro P
are closing in on a tower!
But what awaits them is going to be
an intense showdown with Mikado.
[crowd cheering]
Well, you took your time.
[Iroha] Why are you over here?
If you'd just attack the keep
from the middle, you would've won.
Come on. Where's the fun in that?
We wouldn't be Black onyX
if we didn't keep everyone on their toes.
- [Mikado grunts]
- [Iroha, Kaguya grunt]
[Kaguya wails]
[Kaguya shouts]
No fair! You dodged!
[breathing shakily]
[Iroha] He's too good at this.
Makes sense.
He's been playing video games
for as long as I've known him.
We can't win.
[Otako] Yachiyo, Rai, and Noi
have zero lives left,
which means it's game over
for those players!
The fate of this game now lies
in the hands of the remaining three.
[shouts]
[screams]
Damn it. [inhales sharply]
We'll still win.
[young Iroha grumbles]
[both laugh]
[chuckles]
[groans]
Just so we're clear on this, if we win,
you'll do whatever we want, right?
[scoffs]
[triumphant music plays]
[Iroha shouts]
They switched weapons! [laughs]
[Iroha grunts]
[Mikado] Kaguya's breakthrough power is
the only thing that can destroy the keep.
Therefore, Iroha will sacrifice herself
when the time comes.
I guess, in that case…
- all I gotta do is stop Kaguya.
- [Kaguya screams]
This game is over!
[Iroha] With Kaguya…
[Mikado grunting]
Where'd this wire come from?
Wait, Kaguya was the bait?
[Iroha] If it's Kaguya…
Iroha!
I know exactly what she's thinking.
I know her like no one else does!
- [crowd cheering]
- [Otako] Incredible!
See? I knew you could do it.
[Kaguya pants]
Iroha! [laughs]
We did it!
Nothing can stop us.
[Iroha] No doubt.
[energetic music playing]
[soldiers scream]
Oh…
Mm-hmm.
- [Kaguya shouting]
- [soldiers groaning]
[screams]
Iroha, if you're in danger, don't worry.
I'll help you out.
You better not make a mistake,
or I'll leave you behind.
Why would you do that?
[laughing]
[laughs] Let's go!
Those two are amazing together.
- [gasps]
- I'm definitely a fan for sure.
[Mikado grunts]
[Koto] Mikado is quickly dashing
toward team Kaguya's keep.
[Kaguya] Check out these moves.
This is my moment to shine.
[Koto] Looks at her go.
Kaguya's moving at the speed of light.
Ha-ha! I got you.
Uh…
[Koto wails]
It's a lightning mine trap!
Hmm.
Oh, uh… Damn it.
[Koto] Mikado's almost there!
[dramatic music plays]
[Koto] Yeah! What a turn of events!
The game is over!
The winner is Black onyX!
[crowd cheering]
Uh…
[wails] We lost! No fair.
[whimpers]
Hold on. The results of
the Yachiyo Cup aren't final.
Who will win?
[Yachiyo] What a good game, everyone.
I had so much fun playing KASSEN with you,
but the night isn't over yet.
It's the moment
you've all been waiting for,
and here we go!
The lucky streamer
collaborating with me is…
Drumroll, please…
- [drumroll begins]
- [chuckles]
[Yachiyo] This talented streamer gained
the most followers throughout the event.
YACHIYO CUP RESULTS!
[drumroll continues]
[Yachiyo] Who will it be?
The anticipation is killing me.
The winner of the Yachiyo Cup is…
Kaguya and Iro P!
Congratulations!
[crowd cheering]
What? Didn't we lose though?
I guess not.
[squeals, laughs]
We did it!
[gasps] I can't believe we won.
Yay! Iroha!
- This is all thanks to you!
- [gasps]
What? No. It was all you.
[viewer 1] O-M-G, Iro P is the GOAT!
[viewer 2] She was awesome.
I'm so glad I followed her.
[viewer 3] Wait,
she writes songs for Kaguya too?
- [viewer 1] For reals?
- [viewer 2] I just love her smile.
- [chuckles]
- I'm a huge fan now.
[crowd chanting] Iro P! Kaguya!
Iro P! Kaguya!
I can't wait to sing with you.
[crowd chanting] Iro P! Kaguya!
Iro P! Kaguya!
Gross.
We don't have to get married, do we?
Uh…
Hmm.
It's funny,
this doesn't feel like a victory.
- Uh… Hmm.
- Uh…
[chuckles] Well, don't worry.
I never planned on marrying you
in the first place.
I knew it all along.
[chuckles]
So? Iroha, what was your wish?
Wait, are you serious?
I, um… I want to move to a bigger place.
So, I was wondering if you could be
my co-signer.
Sure you don't want me to buy you a house?
- Uh…
- I want a house. [groans]
You rich kids are all the same.
Thanks, but no thanks.
All righty, then. See you later.
I'm gonna go chat with my fans.
Did you really mean it?
We're getting a bigger place?
Of course. You keep buying more stuff,
and we have no room.
A new home!
- [Yachiyo] Just the girls I'm looking for.
- [Kaguya, Iroha exclaim]
- [laughs]
- [both grunt]
Good job. Congratulations.
Not bad out there,
but if you ask me, you just got lucky.
- [chuckles] Alley-oop.
- [screams] Stop it.
- [exclaiming]
- [grunts] Put me down.
Iroha, Kaguya, you were very impressive.
[chuckles, sighs]
Nah, my skills were so weak
compared to yours.
Yachiyo, how can I learn to move like you?
Practice makes perfect, as they say.
You just have to get out there and do it.
- Ebb and flow like the waves of the ocean.
- [whimpers]
You're perfect,
so that's easy for you to say.
Uh… [chuckles]
I'm not perfect. One of my weaknesses is
I can be very indecisive.
But you're strong. The reason
you're strong is because you're Kaguya.
And Kaguya is strong.
Sorry, not following ya.
- [grunts] Stop poking me. Let me go.
- [chuckles]
Now then,
as we reach the climax of our story,
from here on out,
things might get a little intense.
I sincerely hope you'll follow our tale
to the very end.
Yo!
Are you both prepared to be tossed around
by the tidal waves of fate?
Yeah! [exclaims]
- [chuckles]
- Ah…
Time for bed.
[giggles, yawns]
Good night. See you later.
Is this reality?
Virtual reality!
[gasps]
All right, meet you over there.
[energetic music playing]
- You got it?
- Yup.
There, the fridge can go
in the back of the kitchen.
'Kay.
[exclaiming, laughing]
I feel fantastic,
like everything is perfect, you know?
[Iroha]
Meanwhile, I'm one big stress ball.
[chuckles]
Wow! This is amazing! [laughs]
MATH I+A
[sighs]
We ran out of shampoo,
so I'm gonna run to the store.
I want to go with you
'cause I'll be lonely!
Mmm. Oh, no. We still have
a ton of unpacking to do.
[groans]
PANCAKE MIX
I should get that for her.
[grunts] No, no, wait a minute.
What am I thinking?
Iroha!
Kaguya, where did you come from? [groans]
Bored without you,
so I wanted to come find you.
Hey, hey… [laughs]
What are you doing?
Stop it, that's dangerous!
- [both clamor, shout]
- ♪ Happy synthesizer, hear it now ♪
♪ I'll make a joyful melody ♪
♪ I'll play it for you ♪
♪ You don't need to wear a brave face ♪
- Wah!
- ♪ You don't need to hide from me ♪
♪ All you have to do is be
The person you are ♪
♪ I'm not that smart or talented
But there's one thing I can do ♪
Yummy!
♪ So whatever it's worth
I'll do it for you ♪
Let's go, Kaguya! Number one!
Ten more and I'll be the best!
[both laughing]
IROHA
- [grunting]
- [game beeps]
- Mmm?
- [footsteps approaching]
Iroha, what's this?
Mmm, stop snooping through my files.
Uh…
- UNTITLED (COLLAB WITH IROHA).
- WAV
It looks like it's only half done.
Where's the rest?
Sorry.
I don't have any free time to finish this.
Never mind that. Tomorrow's the big day.
We should get some sleep.
It's not fair, the songs for the concert
are super hard,
but since Yachiyo's AI,
she can handle them no problem.
Mmm.
So much has happened since you arrived
that I can barely keep up with it all.
Iroha, are you sure you're gonna be
okay with tomorrow's schedule?
Uh…
Well, if it's just this once.
CONCERT
MOCK EXAM
- [giggles]
- Ugh…
For real? What's the point
in having separate rooms?
Why me? [chuckles]
[trills] Crab! [trills] Rabbit!
Oh, yeah. That's really cute. Adorable.
All this practicing is making me hungry.
Do you want to get some pancakes
when the concert's done?
Uh… Hmm.
That sounds like a good idea.
I was too nervous to eat today.
[trills] A loach!
- Uh…
- Sorry for the wait.
Pancakes sound absolutely delicious!
I'd love to have some too!
You wanna eat with us?
[chuckles] Oh, my, my…
I'm a performer
who only exists in the digital seas,
so, alas, I don't eat.
No! What kind of torture is that?
There's no way I'd be able to handle that!
Now then, shall we go?
- [breathing heavily]
- [giggles] Oh?
[exhales deeply] Hmm.
- [gasps, laughs]
- Oh.
[Kaguya] Hmm.
I still get nervous
every time I'm up here.
It's the atmosphere.
Yachiyo.
Yes, what's on your mind?
Your debut song, "Remember,"
why don't you sing it anymore?
[chuckles]
That song's job is already done.
It's found its proper place.
[gasps]
- Ready? It's time!
- [Kaguya squeals]
[crowd cheering]
[Yachiyo] Hi, everyone!
Tell me, how's it going out there?
Is life treating you well?
Or do you maybe feel like crying?
[audience member 1] We love you so much!
There, there. It'll be okay.
Even if the journey gets lonely,
the memories of happier times
will light your way and guide your path.
[chuckles]
I want to make this
a memory you will never forget.
So please, will you dance with me?
♪ You know that I'm
The world's number-one best princess ♪
- ♪ That's how you need to treat me ♪
- [Kaguya giggles]
♪ 'Cause you gotta be obsessed ♪
♪ Got it? ♪
♪ Number 1, you gotta notice
When I come into the room ♪
♪ With a different hairdo ♪
♪ Number 2, you've got to notice
When I get cute, new shoes ♪
♪ Number 3
You gotta say some special things to me ♪
♪ Just a little talking sweet
Is all you gotta do ♪
♪ If you understand ♪
♪ I don't know what you're waiting for
Boy, just grab my hand ♪
Hey, come on!
♪ And it's not like I'm selfish ♪
♪ I just want a little bit of spice ♪
♪ I want you to think
That I'm the cutest girl ♪
♪ That you've ever seen
In all of your life ♪
Hey, hey, it's okay if you love me
more than anyone else in the world!
♪ You know that I'm
The world's number-one best princess ♪
♪ Notice me
Hey, hey, hey, hey! ♪
♪ You better not make a girl wait ♪
♪ Number 1, for sure
You better bet that I'm ready to go ♪
- ♪ Are you listening? ♪
- [Kaguya vocalizes, laughs]
♪ I got an appetite for something sweet ♪
♪ You know I want it now! ♪
[Yachiyo] Yeah!
Hey, baby
- [Yachiyo] This next one's a new song.
- [Kaguya] Here we go!
[crowd cheering]
Breakdown!
[song ends]
["Ex-Otogibanashi" plays]
♪ There's a story that's told
And it's as old as time ♪
♪ Everybody knows ♪
♪ Kaguya, the princess
She herself was the one who had said it ♪
♪ I don't want it to end like that
I refuse for it to end that way ♪
♪ Would you just nod your head ♪
♪ And sit back
And accept that it's only fate? ♪
♪ It's not a story someone wrote
'Cause your life is up to you ♪
♪ You can write your own
Only you and me ♪
♪ It's a journey we go through
It's nostalgic and it's new ♪
♪ That's the kind
Kind of song that we sing ♪
♪ I pictured this year with you
Before a million times ♪
♪ But you know it's still
My sweetest memory ♪
♪ Seven sparkling colors shining bright ♪
♪ Lighting up our special, sweet fantasy ♪
♪ Yeah, you know it, I'm the heroine ♪
♪ And I'll pierce your heart
With the strongest melody ♪
♪ Don't pretend you don't know who I am ♪
♪ Say my name, say my name
'Cause I deserve the fame ♪
♪ I'm the best
I'm the princess every single day! ♪
♪ Hey, you only get one go around ♪
♪ So you better live
Right here, right now ♪
- ♪ Now ♪
- [Kaguya giggles]
♪ We only get one life, you know ♪
♪ And for forever I waited
For this very opportunity ♪
♪ It's the sweet fantasy ♪
♪ 'Cause that's me ♪
♪ It's the sweet ♪
♪ Fantasy ♪
[song ends]
- [crowd cheering]
- [audience member 2] Yachiyo!
[audience member 3] Kaguya!
[both panting]
[chuckles] Oh, man. That was awesome.
Iroha, love you.
You what?
You know,
I think maybe I should just marry you.
Wha…
- [giggles]
- No, then?
I guess, if you pay half the rent
and bills and stuff,
I don't mind us living together.
Wait, really?
[thunder rumbling]
[mysterious music playing]
[bystander 1] The Internet went out.
[bystander 2] What is that?
- [shouts]
- [exclaiming]
Uh, I'm sorry.
Uh… [gasps, groans]
[crowd gasping, shouting]
[Iroha] Huh, what are those?
Uh… [gasps]
Kaguya!
[gasps]
Come on, now. That's no way to behave.
We are sorry.
- [crowd exclaiming]
- [gasps]
You really never know
what's going to happen next!
- So stay tuned for more updates.
- That's part of the show?
- I don't know.
- I guess Yachiyo loves a show.
[giggles] Hey, I hope you all
enjoyed the performance.
- [Kaguya] Uh…
- [crowd cheering]
[gasps] Yachiyo, what was that?
Hmm.
It's possible it was a glitch
or just some kids messing around?
I'll look into it!
And in other news,
Tachikawa City, Tokyo experienced
a widespread failure…
- I…
- …of communication devices
at 10:00 p.m. this evening.
- I can't believe the concert's over.
- Hmm.
Yeah, but there are still lots and lots
of things that I want to do,
and more ingredients
are getting delivered tomorrow!
Such a greedy little monster.
- [roars]
- [chuckles]
The hijacking will be investigated…
MYSTERY NETWORK OUTAGE
You feeling okay?
TACHIKAWA, TOKYO
- Several surveillance cameras…
- [Kaguya] I'm just tired, that's all.
…recorded the same eerie footage.
Good night!
[anchor] This strange image of the moon
was recorded from a digital sign in town.
- [sighs]
- Citizens who were wearing smart contacts…
MOM - MISSED CALLS (10)
…have reported their concern
after witnessing…
"What I want to do…"
[anchor] Stay tuned for the weather…
- What on earth is that?
- Hmm?
Sweet sea bream!
Is it okay if I grill it over charcoal?
Not okay.
[sighs] I'm going out for a while.
[Kaguya] Hmm? Have fun!
See you later.
[door closes]
Hmm.
[gasps]
Hmm?
The same goes for,
"su," "sasu," and "shimu."
They can all be used to mean something
that is outside of one's own control.
For example, in the case of
"se tamou" or "rare tamou"…
Yesterday's concert was amazing.
You were both so good.
Iroha, your performance was so good,
you brought us to tears! [giggles]
I'd give it a gold star for sure.
[chuckles] Thank you.
So, anyway, where's Kaguya?
She was filleting a fish last I saw her.
- Eh…
- Hmm…
Hmm?
9/1 - FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
[Roka] How about some fireworks
to end summer with a bang?
It's about an hour away by train.
All of us?
[Mami] No, no. We have
an important mission to take care of.
[Roka] We completely neglected
all our summer homework.
So what do you think?
It's your call.
[chuckles]
Mmm.
DAY OFF
MOCK EXAM
Looks like I have my own trouble.
Hey, Kaguya. How's it going out here?
Oh. [giggles]
Iroha, you are right on time.
- Here.
- [bites, chews]
Tasty. What is it?
And tomorrow,
I'll make ramen from scratch! [chuckles]
Awesome.
Mmm.
Want to go?
I…
Yay! Yay! Yay!
[gentle music playing]
I love it!
You don't think I look a bit weird?
No!
- You look great in anything!
- [groans]
[Kaguya giggles]
[humming and laughing]
[gasps]
RAINBOW MIX
[Kaguya] There's really no substitute
for real life.
[exclaims]
[Iroha] Sure, but Tsukuyomi
is pretty good too, right?
LIGHT BULB SODA
Wow, this is so fun!
A kingdom of fun.
Hey, are you copying me? [laughs]
You never take that thing off, do you?
Uh, oh…
It makes me feel calm.
It's like a little piece of home.
[announcer] Welcome to
the 25th Satomi Fireworks Festival.
Hey, did you know, on the moon
we don't have any sense of taste
or temperature?
Everyone just repeats their roles
over and over again.
It's so boring.
[announcer] With the hope
that each light will become a flower…
I can't imagine what that's like.
[announcer]
So with no further ado, is everyone ready?
I was always the odd one.
- [spectator 1] Oh, there they are.
- [spectator 2] Look, it's starting.
[spectators gasping, laughing]
[giggles]
[Kaguya] It gets lonely and boring.
Having to repeat the same things
every day, it was killing me.
Finally, I'd had enough.
I wanted to go somewhere. Anywhere.
FIREWORKS FESTIVAL
[Kaguya]
I looked out the window into your world
at all the people
doing whatever they pleased.
Their lives were complex, fleeting
and, best of all, free.
But…
I could tell they were also
holding back their emotions.
Waiting for something more important.
Then what? You grew up?
[laughs] I'm copying you.
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
Do you love your mom, Iroha?
[Iroha] Do I love her?
I don't know. I really don't.
[inhales sharply, sobs]
So many times…
I thought it would be easier
if I could just hate her.
[sobs]
You know something,
now I'm feeling even more sorry for you.
Sorry I brought it up.
I'm surprised you didn't get mad at me.
"You just don't understand, Kaguya."
That's what you wanted to say, right?
[Iroha] No…
I didn't want to say that.
You just don't understand yet.
[Iroha] I never wanted to say that.
[Kaguya] I see.
[Iroha] Kaguya.
Are you going home?
[Kaguya] Well, I kinda ditched work
to come here, so…
It's like forced deportation. [chuckles]
Guess I am Princess Kaguya, after all.
During the next full moon,
they'll come for me.
They'll come to our house?
Mmm, they'll probably come to Tsukuyomi.
The virtual world is much closer
to the moon than your world.
[Iroha] You could just run away again.
There's no way
you're the real Princess Kaguya.
You're too crazy and chaotic.
There's no way that you're the same person
from the fairy tale.
[giggles]
[Kaguya] And so the chaotic Princess
Kaguya was summoned back to the moon,
but she swore that she would
make her final days an absolute blast.
[giggles]
That's how it should have ended.
That's the ending for me.
Enjoying every second
as I charge towards destiny.
[gasps]
But if I'm being honest,
I wanted to spend more time
singing with you, Iroha!
- All the new songs as well.
- Huh.
I know. When they do come,
let's do a big concert, okay?
[Kaguya screams]
I felt that one! And smell that smoke!
[gasps] It's amazing!
We should probably head home
before it gets too late.
[Iroha] Guess real life
is finally catching up with me.
KAGUYA ANNOUNCES HER GRADUATION!
Time to go back to my old self.
I can get back to studying and work.
[Kaguya] Crabs!
- [Iroha] I'm home.
- Crabs, crabs.
Hi.
- [laughs]
- What are you doing?
Playing with the crabs.
Uh…
Want to make a song?
- A new one?
- What?
Really?
Yahoo! [laughing]
I can't promise you
it'll be any good though.
What should we write?
I know, how about that song
you never finished?
Uh, hmm…
Mmm…
Hmm…
Iroha! Let's… Uh…
- [sighs]
- Oh. [chuckles]
[cackles]
EASY CHAR SIU
LOTS OF PORK BELLY
Hmm.
I wonder if I can take InuDOGE home too.
[Mikado] Aw, man!
I can't believe
that Kaguya's really a moon princess.
It makes sense.
Wow, so then Kaguya really was
from the moon.
No wonder her skin was perfect,
even at the beach.
Yachiyo, do you think
we'll be able to protect Kaguya?
I looked into it,
but I can't even figure out how
they managed to get into Tsukuyomi.
I'm sorry.
[Iroha] It's okay.
Well, they can't grab her
in the real world, ain't that right?
So how about
we just take them out in here?
I'll help too.
I don't know how useful I'll be…
but I'll do my best.
Okay. Let's get ready. Noi?
Aw, man. That thing's such a pain though.
- [Mikado] Just follow orders.
- [Noi] Okay, okay.
[Roka] Iroha.
Let's all go to the beach again next year.
And the hot springs too!
[Iroha] Thank you.
Oh, mmm…
I'm sorry, Yachiyo.
Can I ask you for one more favor?
- Huh? Oh.
- [pop music plays through headphones]
[gasps] Wow, is that the song?
Yeah…
It's actually a song
I had been working on with my dad.
It's my first song.
After my Dad died,
I wrote a few other songs,
but they never felt quite right,
so I stopped writing.
But now I can't remember
just how the song ends.
[sighs] Hmm.
Don't worry. That's why I'm here.
I'll write the rest of the lyrics for you.
Together, I just know
we're gonna make your dad proud.
♪ Smack your hand up the wall ♪
♪ And add some spice
To make your life feel way more exciting ♪
That works, right?
[chuckles] Maybe it does.
Oh, guess what, Yachiyo agreed
to produce our next live concert.
What? No way! You asked her?
Leave everything to me!
Awesome! I have to start coming up
with the choreography!
Uh…
[chuckles] Well, in that case,
I'd better finish this song.
[sighing]
[desk clatters]
On second thought, maybe that's too much.
One chorus at a time.
[energetic pop music playing]
[gasps]
[music stops]
[energetic melody plays]
[soft melody plays]
[no audible dialogue]
The same melody?
But why?
[Kaguya hums melody]
Check, check, check. Mic test!
[humming]
[gasps]
Kaguya?
[breathes shakily]
- Yeah?
- [yelps]
[groans]
Don't scare me like that.
[gasps, chuckles]
Here, this is for you.
- Oh. You're sure?
- [chuckles]
Thank you.
[Kaguya] The concert's gonna be here?
That's what Iroha wanted.
Yachiyo!
[chuckles] Nothing to worry about,
you little cutie.
[FUSHI] Hey, don't get too cocky,
you little mutt.
[InuDOGE barks]
I wonder if they'd love me more,
if I was just like you, Yachiyo.
Hmm.
No, no.
This is all happening thanks to you.
Off you go, Kaguya.
It's all going to work out,
because I know you.
[chuckles]
That's reckless. [laughs]
But, sometimes, that's the best way to be.
[Otako] What a crazy turn of events!
It's the graduation concert
of the superstar Kaguya,
the girl who came out of nowhere
and touched all our hearts.
But this is not the time to cry.
Kaguya's last show, let's make it count!
- [crowd cheering]
- [fan 1] Kaguya!
[fan 2] I love you!
Everybody, thank you!
Looks like it's time to say goodbye,
but please don't be sad.
Graduations are happy events.
So please see me off with a smile.
- [whooshing overhead]
- Uh…
[all giggle]
[Mami, Roka] Yay!
Mind if we join you?
Kaguya, we're gonna do our best
to keep you with us.
[gasps]
[Iroha] And if we win,
we can celebrate with pancakes
and shopping at Donki.
It's not "if" we win, you know?
[Iroha scoffs]
I see… Okay!
[laughing]
This is freedom!
[mysterious music playing]
[pop music playing]
[Iroha] Are they here to take Kaguya home?
[Mikado] Time to get this party started!
♪ No matter what tomorrow holds ♪
♪ Let's live in the moment ♪
♪ So we can smile and joy unfolds ♪
♪ It's my decision, not a game ♪
♪ But I end up dreaming ♪
♪ About a day that stays the same ♪
♪ With many more impulsive melodies ♪
♪ With heartfelt songs
And tender harmonies ♪
♪ The brightest symphony
For us to say goodbye ♪
♪ The scenes I carried in my mind
I long to see one day ♪
♪ Were more beautiful and hard to define ♪
♪ Free in many different ways ♪
♪ When a thousand years are gone
And ten thousand fade from sight ♪
♪ Still this single second lives on
Forever, shining through the night ♪
♪ A time to start anew
And a time when things are through ♪
♪ Now I see you looking at me gently ♪
♪ And it warms my heart ♪
♪ So if this is my fate
Then I will embrace the call… ♪
- [Iroha] I won't let this end badly!
- ♪ I'll try to open myself to it all ♪
♪ Ah, look how this land
Fills up with colors ♪
♪ That have re-emerged ♪
♪ Bringing a light to all the tears
And smiles in all the world ♪
[music ends]
[sighs, grunts]
["Reply" plays]
♪ In your eyes I can see
All the quiet in the world ♪
♪ And how did I never see before ♪
[Kaguya] Iroha,
you're more beautiful than you know.
I fell in love with you
the moment I saw you.
♪ I know I've been self-obsessed ♪
♪ I know that I screwed around ♪
♪ But we've gotta catch that colorfulness
That's nowhere to be found ♪
♪ Let's go ♪
♪ 'Cause there's nothing better
In this world ♪
♪ Than right here, right now ♪
♪ Gotta hold on tight to the moment ♪
♪ Hold on to the golden days we find ♪
♪ Come on, let's share all our dreams ♪
♪ And we can act like queens and kings ♪
♪ And we can keep ourselves ♪
♪ Surrounded by the love
We find in everyday things ♪
♪ Every memory is a sweet daydream ♪
♪ I cherish all of ours ♪
♪ We can keep them all in our hearts ♪
♪ Protected like the treasures
That they are ♪
♪ Come on, let's party some more ♪
♪ And when we're done, sing an encore ♪
♪ And we'll get everything
We're wishing for ♪
♪ We're shining stars
When we sing our song ♪
[music ends]
[ethereal chiming]
You've traveled a long way.
I'm sorry that I ran away,
but I've had such an awesome time
while I was here.
[ethereal chiming]
No, wait.
Don't go. There's more you wanted to do.
This was the best graduation ever!
So many memories I'll never forget.
Thank you, everyone!
- [fan 3] Kaguya!
- [fan 4] I love you!
- [fan 5] Don't go. [cries]
- [laughs]
Saying goodbye is hard,
and all things end.
Don't forget…
Iroha. I love you.
- Bye-bye!
- [crowd cheering]
[whimpers]
[fan 6] What a show!
It's like she really was Princess Kaguya.
- [fan 7] It's like a dream!
- [fan 8] I'll never recover! [cries]
No, is this really your last bow?
Listen, all of you fought well.
Thank you so much.
[chuckles]
Hmm.
It's time to go home.
- I'm sorry.
- [all gasp]
- [vocalizes]
- [Iroha] Spends my money without asking.
- [laughs]
- Does whatever she wants.
Never cleans up.
NO MAYO/KETCHUP ALLOWED
[Iroha] She's such a pain.
- [sighs]
- Seriously…
the absolute worst.
- [phone buzzes]
- [gasps]
YOU'VE RECEIVED A PAYMENT
HERE'S ALL THE MONEY I OWE YOU!
SORRY FOR THE TROUBLE!
I can't spend that.
Oh, you dummy. It's too much.
[sighs]
[calm music playing]
TARGET SCHOOL LIST
[teacher]
So you decided on law school, huh?
Sorry it took so long.
There's been a lot going on.
You've always been a perfect student.
I'm glad you had a distraction.
Yeah, but that's behind me now.
I'm all ready to get to work.
Is there any advice on
how to prep for entrance exams?
Of course!
I'm sorry I ghosted you.
So mean.
I was gonna go break down your door.
I'm really, really sorry.
[chuckles] All that matters…
Is that our friend is feeling better.
[gasps]
[sobs]
[Yachiyo] Just like that, the fairy-tale
days of life with Kaguya were over.
Life went back to normal for Iroha.
That was the story of Iroha
and Princess Kaguya.
[Iroha] Kaguya, you may not be with me,
but I'll carry you in my heart forever!
AND SHE LIVED HAPPILY EVER AFTER
"COOLNESS" IS THE THEME OF
THE BLACK ONYX SPECIAL 3RD LIVE.
There's no way
I'm letting it end like this.
I can't!
[energetic music playing]
I need more time to decide.
[teacher] Take all the time you need.
[Kaguya] I wanted to spend more time
singing with you, Iroha.
[Iroha] I want that too.
I want…
[grunts]
I don't need a happy ending.
A normal ending is perfectly fine with me.
I HAVE A MIGRAINE,
SO I'LL NEED TO MISS WORK…
[Kaguya] That's the ending for me!
Enjoying every second
as I charge towards destiny!
MOM - SWIPE TO ANSWER
I don't think so.
No.
[line ringing]
[no audible dialogue]
[Mom] All right. Go ahead.
[gasps]
I did it.
I told her.
♪ All that I wanted from you ♪
♪ Was to get back to us too ♪
♪ And it might sound so cliche ♪
♪ But we felt right yesterday ♪
♪ Let me know how you really feel ♪
♪ And we can make this dream a reality ♪
[gasps] Iroha!
[Iroha] ♪ Hey there ♪
♪ We can make this moment now
The greatest in the world ♪
- [Kaguya] Well, in that case, let's go!
- [Iroha singing]
♪ We can walk together down the road ♪
♪ If we can just let our hearts sing ♪
♪ Keep all of our faces smiling ♪
♪ And we can keep ourselves ♪
♪ Surrounded by the love
We find in everyday things ♪
[sighs]
YACHIYO RUNAMI - SENDING…
UNABLE TO SEND
[gasps, sighs]
[chiming]
[Yachiyo] I've been practicing
the Loach Scooping dance lately!
It's pretty funny!
Do you want me to show you?
Here we go! Hey there!
Come on!
- [sighs]
- Let's go. Come on.
Come back. How are you all by yourself?
Tell me where she is.
[sighs]
I'll find her myself.
Don't be dumb. Where would you even look?
I don't care.
I'll search the whole world if I have to.
[FUSHI] Open your eyes.
Over here!
Hey! [groans]
Let me get dressed first.
- [door unlocks]
- [gasps]
That's how you get in.
[grunts]
Kaguya?
[gasps]
Yachiyo.
Are you… Are you Kaguya?
I know it must sound crazy, but…
are you?
[gentle music playing]
A long time ago,
Kaguya was once again on the moon
working as a corporate slave
when a beautiful song reached her ears.
She decided right then to return to Earth.
So, she wrapped up all of her work
with lightning speed
and handed everything over.
Sadly, too many Earth years had gone by.
Not to worry, because the moon's
technology can transcend time itself.
Princess Kaguya traveled through time
to get here.
But before she could arrive,
her ship crashed into a giant asteroid.
When she finally got to Earth,
she had gone back too far.
8,000 years in the past.
There was not enough power
left in her broken ship,
and only InuDOGE, her faithful companion,
ended up with a body.
Her only way to communicate
with the world,
- was through the body of the sea slug.
- I give glory to you.
Listen up! All you gotta do is go west.
That will solve everything. [grunts]
[Yachiyo] Time passed,
and people developed the technology
to give shape to the invisible,
and connect with each other
across the world.
YACHI8000:
WHY'S IT STILL 1995? :(
[Yachiyo] It was similar to
the world of the moon she knew so well.
For the first time,
Kaguya discovered it was possible
to connect to the world
without a body of her own.
Finally, in the guise of
the songstress of Tsukuyomi,
she was able to
reunite once more with Iroha.
So, there we go, it's not
the simplest happy ending,
but we got there. [chuckles]
Uh, yep.
[Iroha] What about my Kaguya?
[Yachiyo] She's on her journey
of reincarnation once again.
It is a cycle.
One of a destiny that we cannot escape.
That doesn't make any sense.
- [footsteps approach]
- [pants]
It's just a fairy tale.
Don't think too hard about it.
Let's just celebrate our reunion.
You know, I've always loved
the view from up here.
But how?
How can you smile all the time?
That's just part of my nature.
But…
I made a promise…
that there'd be a happy ending for us.
And even though I tried to come back
when I heard your song…
Sorry, I messed up.
The sparkling Princess Kaguya…
is an old lady.
[gasps]
Kaguya…
I've never seen that look
on your face before.
[Yachiyo] Iroha…
If it's too much for you,
you can easily forget.
FUSHI can help…
- Yachiyo!
- [gasps]
[Iroha groans, scoffs]
[groans]
Eight thousand years…
I want to know everything that happened.
I'll stay up all night.
[laughs] Well, there's quite a lot.
Right!
[humming]
Sorry. I guess I still get
quite nostalgic for this place.
- You know?
- [grunts]
It's all fake, though.
I don't care!
Where to begin?
How about the time
I went fishing with the Jomon people?
That long-horned creature…
Now that's a story I remember.
And then that shrimp
with the long whiskers…
[dialogue speeds up rapidly]
…that was a blast.
But Sho was such a mess!
- [groans]
- You know,
you could die from lack of sleep, Iroha.
[groans]
The Edo period. Okay, keep going!
- Go to sleep. Go to sleep.
- Huh?
Oh, no. Looks like
it's just about my bedtime.
[yawns]
Sorry about that.
[Iroha sighs]
You were always so happy.
You grew up to be just like me.
FUSHI. Yachiyo's hiding something from me,
isn't she?
If she didn't tell you, then I…
Show me, FUSHI.
I want to know everything.
[FUSHI] I don't know if a human body
could handle it all.
[Iroha] This is non-negotiable.
Yachiyo, she looked truly happy
for the first time in a really long time.
[inhales deeply] Here we go!
[gasps]
[Kaguya] I wonder where Yachiyo is now…
Please come out.
Help me.
Kaguya!
[Kaguya] Believe it or not,
a girl came out of the utility pole!
[Empress Jingu]
You truly are a sign of good luck.
[Fujiwara] Compared to how I feel now,
after having met you…
There must be someone you're looking for.
[Empress Jingu] Life is hard.
But even when it's painful,
I smile through.
I had hoped to see the era
that would make you smile.
This is where I belong.
[Carter] The best wine
gets better over time.
It's not all bad, you know.
[groans]
[Kaguya] I'm such a dummy.
Why did it take me so long to realize it?
That Yachiyo…
She is…
[chuckles]
[Iroha] I get it now.
That's why Yachiyo
is always smiling so brightly,
why she's so happy.
[laughs]
[water rushing]
[glass shatters]
[Yachiyo] Iroha! Iroha!
Iroha!
[grunts, groans]
You know, I grew up too.
I was even able to talk to my mom.
Even after Kaguya left,
it was a perfectly happy ending.
And now the story is over.
[breathes shakily]
[sobs]
I want her back.
[gasps, sighs]
I thought that I could be happy
with this ending.
♪ Hey there
We can make this moment now ♪
♪ The greatest in the world ♪
I remembered every word.
♪ In our hearts
We've all got a song ♪
♪ It's a precious melody ♪
♪ Straight from your soul ♪
♪ Singing so sweet ♪
I survived because of this song.
I always wondered if your hands
would be warm to touch.
I want to eat pancakes with you once more.
Right, okay.
Here's the thing.
I know that our story is not over yet.
I found something else that I want to do.
So you have to stick with me
until we get the real happy ending.
[upbeat electronic music plays]
[no audible dialogue]
SHUT UP…
KURAKAWA HIGH SCHOOL
[no audible dialogue]
[music continues]
TEN YEARS LATER
Big brother, we're so close
to the final breakthrough.
- Huh?
- Let me be more clear.
I need you to invest in me.
I won't let you down!
Hang on a second.
What do you think I am,
some kind of billionaire?
You'll figure it out.
I believe in you. You can do it!
- You know, you…
- [Iroha] I what?
Nothing.
Okay, I'll figure something out.
Can I have an avatar body as well?
Noi and I will help out too.
[Noi] Huh? I will?
[Rai] It's nice to do a good deed
every now and then.
- [chuckles]
- Yeah, helping's not really my thing.
- [Akira] All right, we'll be back soon.
- [Rai] Excuse us.
- Wait a minute, was that…
- [Iroha] My brother.
[giggles]
I can see why he's popular.
[Mami] That means
the other two with him were…
[Mami shrieks]
Guess you're not shy anymore, Iroha.
Well, a lot has happened over the years.
You never know,
I might have surpassed even you, Yachiyo.
Okay, work's done for the day.
Time to head home.
Gotta have a work-life balance.
Morning!
[groans]
Wow, it's heavy.
It fits you better than the last model.
Oh! Pancakes!
We haven't quite worked out
the sense of taste.
Oh, I don't want to wait another second!
[chuckles]
[Otako] I can't believe I'm alive to
see this day… Kaguya's comeback concert!
Airing in both the real world
and Tsukuyomi!
And Yachiyo will be dancing with her!
[Kaguya] It's been so long!
[Iroha] Only 8,000 years.
[Yachiyo] That's only last week for me.
[giggling]
[crowd cheering]
Let's go!
[Kaguya] So what do you think?
Is this the story's happily ever after?
What if after the concert,
they have a fight and break up?
[laughs] There's just
no way to know for sure.
It's the same for your story, right?
For now, this is the end of our story.
The title?
The title is…
COSMIC PRINCESS KAGUYA!
♪ I feel like when we parted was longer ♪
♪ Longer ago than it must've been ♪
♪ Kept that sad, lonely light
All sealed away inside ♪
♪ And I stamped my foot
Till my heel hurt ♪
♪ Oh, I could still see it
When I was with you ♪
♪ Now I can't see it again anymore ♪
♪ Staring off at that comet
Invisible and bright ♪
♪ Now I'm searching desperately
For it still ♪
♪ I sang and I sang so many songs ♪
♪ Melodies that I can't ever sing again ♪
♪ I wasn't lonely even a bit ♪
♪ Now I know what it's like
To be lonely for real ♪
♪ Don't know how long it's been
Don't know how far I've gone ♪
♪ I don't even know
What's right or what's wrong ♪
♪ I don't even have
The time to stop and think ♪
♪ I'm just making my feet
Keep walking on ♪
♪ I want to spend my time
Just having fun ♪
♪ Brushing all my troubles off
With a laugh ♪
♪ It'll be okay
This pain won't go away ♪
♪ Even if I forget, it'll stay with me ♪
♪ We built a road of pretty ideals, but ♪
♪ Here comes reality wiping it clean ♪
♪ But our memories linger
Shining in our wake ♪
♪ They'll keep lighting the way
Forevermore ♪
♪ Oh, why did we end up
Losing each other? ♪
♪ Why did we have to part ways
Back then? ♪
♪ Now that sad, lonely light ♪
♪ Makes my shadow stretch and grow ♪
♪ Looming tall and deep there
In front of me ♪
♪ Sometimes there's
A fever burning inside ♪
♪ And I'll try to sleep
When I find the time ♪
♪ Even knowing that all this
Is only a dream ♪
♪ I want to find you there
And set out again ♪
♪ Far, far away from
The boundless open sky ♪
♪ Even in the endless depths of the dark ♪
♪ All I need to do
Is think about those stars ♪
♪ And I'm there
In the glow of the galaxy ♪
♪ Even if I stop just crying
All the time ♪
♪ Even if I buy a new pair of shoes ♪
♪ It'll be okay
This pain won't go away ♪
♪ Even if I forget, it'll stay with me ♪
♪ I know there was something ♪
♪ You wanted to tell me ♪
♪ All that time ago ♪
♪ It was probably some old silly cliche ♪
♪ But I wanna know
I've gotta know ♪
♪ I know that our meetings and partings ♪
♪ Are always two parts of a single whole ♪
♪ That invisible comet
Is still out there ♪
♪ It's invisible, so it's never gone ♪
♪ A or B or C
I don't know which is right ♪
♪ I don't know what answers everyone had ♪
♪ I don't even have
The time to stop and check ♪
♪ I'm just living my life
With all I've got ♪
♪ Even if I stop just crying
All the while ♪
♪ Even if I brush things off
With a smile ♪
♪ It'll be okay
This pain won't go away ♪
♪ Even if I forget, it'll stay with me ♪
♪ It'll be all right
I see this ray of light ♪
♪ And I know at the start ♪
♪ You're standing there ♪
♪ Melting, I feel like I might melt away ♪
♪ Melting ♪
♪ Each morning when I wake up ♪
♪ The very first thing I think of is you ♪
♪ Just you, always you ♪
♪ I thought I'd make a change ♪
♪ Kept hoping you'd notice
And ask me "What's up?" ♪
♪ "Why did you cut your bangs?" ♪
♪ My pretty flowy pink skirt ♪
♪ My shiny flower hairpin ♪
♪ I'll put them on when I go out ♪
♪ Today ♪
♪ I just want to look so cute for you ♪
♪ Melting, I feel like I might melt away ♪
♪ Can't ever tell you I love you ♪
♪ Can't tell you how I feel, but ♪
♪ Melting, can't even look you
In the eye ♪
♪ I'm not in love with love ♪
♪ I'm just in love with you ♪
♪ You're all that I've got
In my heart now ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ The weather forecast ♪
♪ Was lying to me ♪
♪ It's raining cats and dogs out here ♪
♪ Right now ♪
♪ Right there in my school bag ♪
♪ My umbrella is packed ♪
♪ But I'm not pleased at all ♪
♪ I let out a sigh ♪
♪ That's when you show up ♪
♪ "I guess I'll have to share" ♪
♪ "You can come walk under mine with me" ♪
♪ You give a little smile
You're right there by my side ♪
♪ I can hear the sound
Of me falling in love ♪
♪ The sound of me falling in love ♪
♪ Falling in love ♪
♪ Melting, I feel like I might suffocate ♪
♪ My right hand's at my side ♪
♪ It's touching you ♪
♪ And trembling ♪
♪ My heart is beating loud ♪
♪ Beneath this shared umbrella ♪
♪ Now I'm so close to you ♪
♪ I could reach my hand ♪
♪ Oh, gosh, what now? ♪
♪ I just want my feelings to reach you ♪
♪ God, if you can hear me, please ♪
♪ Let time stand still ♪
♪ Feel like I could cry ♪
♪ But I'm happy ♪
♪ It might just kill me! ♪
♪ Melting
We're almost to the station now ♪
♪ We'll never meet again ♪
♪ You're here right now ♪
♪ So close and yet so far, so ♪
♪ Melting ♪
♪ Let's hold hands
While you walk with me! ♪
♪ Oh, tell me, do we really ♪
♪ Have to say goodbye now? ♪
♪ Please hold me tight ♪
♪ Wrap me in your arms this instant! ♪
♪ Just kidding ♪
[Yachiyo] Even after 8,000 years,
all I can think about is eating fluffy,
yummy pancakes.
I'll never forget those delicious,
perfect, happy…
- [Iroha] You're so extra!
- [Yachiyo laughs]
[Iroha, Yachiyo laughing]